ALEXANDER LAMBROW

Full-Stack Software Developer

alexander.lambrow@gmail.com

(410) 206—7229

alexanderlambrow.com

in linkedin.com/in/alexander-lambrow/

github.com/alambrow

Projects

VibeHunt

| Codebase | View Live |

Finding the right place to go out in the evening has again become an issue. This app aggregates real-time data from the BestTime and Google Maps APIs to help users select the venues with the best vibe for an evening out and about in Nashville, TN.

Tech stack: React.js, Python/Django, Google Maps API, BestTime API

LevelUp

| Codebase | View Live |

A full-stack scheduler that allows users to create games and to host events. Register an account and join in on a game.

Tech stack: React.js, Python/Django, Material-Ul

Truncheons and Flagons

| Codebase | View Live |

A medieval drinking game gone digital. Built by a team of four, this app employs Vanilla JavaScript and JSON Server to guide users through three rounds of a mock beer pong tournament.

Tech stack: JavaScript, JSON Server

ABOUT

I am a humanities Ph.D. and former university lecturer who has transitioned into software development over the past year. Since joining Nashville Software School this spring, I have been thrilled to see that the skills I developed in my first career—self-teaching, fastidious research, careful editing, and clear communication—translate well into the world of computer science. I feel fortunate to have found another line of work that allows me to continue learning and solving problems.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- Python
- Git/Github

- React.js
- DjangoSQL
- Scrum/Agile

- HTML5CSS3
- C

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | April 2021—September 2021

Full-time coding bootcamp, with a focus on teaching full-stack development through self-guided, project-based work

- Worked individually and on small teams to develop single-page web applications with full CRUD functionality
- Managed workflow through GitHub Projects
- Planned data structures (ERDs)
- Implemented data servers in Vanilla Python and Django
- Worked with external APIs like Google Maps API and BestTime API
- · Styled web pages with CSS3 and React-Bootstrap

EDUCATION

HARVARD UNIVERSITY

Ph.D. German Literature (2019)

UC, BERKELEY

M.A. German Studies (2013)

DARTMOUTH COLLEGE

B.A. Comparative Literature (2010) magna cum laude, Phi Beta Kappa

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

APPLICATION MENTOR Crimson Education | June 2019—present

Web-based university admissions consulting company specializing in assisting college-bound students improve their personal profiles and gain admission to highly selective B.A. programs

- Worked on teams of three to advise students on winning admissions strategies
- Specialized in essay writing, leading each student through an intensive, six-month brainstorming, writing, and editing process
- Coordinated work with 12+ teams/students at any given time

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONT.)

POSTDOCTORAL SCHOLAR / LECTURER Vanderbilt University | August 2019—December 2020

- Instructed five undergraduate-level courses in German language and cultural history in the College of Arts & Science
- Conducted independent research in intellectual history, resulting in two articles and a book (forthcoming):
 - Sample work: "The Seriousness of Play: Johann Huizinga and Carl Schmitt on Play and the Political," Games and Culture 2020 | View Online |
- Presented research at international conference (NeMLA 2020)
- · Assisted in the development of future courses as member of Undergraduate Curriculum Planning Committee

TEACHING FELLOW / LECTURER Harvard University | August 2015—August 2019

- Taught twelve undergraduate-level courses in German language and cultural history at Harvard College and Harvard Summer School, including multiple 20-hour/week intensive courses; won a teaching prize for every semester of instruction
- Conducted independent research in cultural and intellectual history, resulting in one highly cited article and a 50,000-word dissertation:
 - o "14 December 1930: Robert Musil Meets Carl Schmitt" German Quarterly 2017 | View Online |
 - "Theogony ab ovo: Carl Schmitt's Political Aesthetics" (Dissertation) | View Online |
- Presented research at ten major academic conferences (ACLA, GSA, NeMLA)
- Hosted local chapter of the working group BTWH (Berkeley-Tübingen-Wien-Harvard); planned and secured over \$10,000 in grant funding for 2016 annual conference held in Cambridge, MA; organized discussions and social events for attendees
- Bernhard Blume Award (2016—2017) for "excellence in study of Germanic languages and literatures"

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT University of California, Berkeley | August 2012—May 2013

- Instructed two undergraduate-level courses in German language
- Planned and secured \$8,000 in grant funding for academic conference on "Laughter" in German film and literature, held on Berkeley campus in 2013; invited keynote speaker from external institution; organized discussions and social events for attendees

Fulbright Fellow

U.S. Department of State | August 2010—June 2011

- Awarded fellowship to spend the year after college in Dresden, Germany, as a representative of the United States
- Worked as English-language teaching assistant in binational German-Czech secondary school